Yulia Afletunova

Data Scientist

Berlin, Germany (with work permit)

■ afletunova.yulia@gmail.com In linkedin.com/in/afletunova

ABOUT

Experienced Data Analyst with 5+ years in analytics engineering and product analytics. Seeking a versatile role to apply my skills, drive positive change, and provide data-driven insights. Keen about learning and sharing knowledge, and founded Analyst Girls Club, a community for women in this field.

EXPERIENCE

• Data Analyst (Analyst-Developer)

Apr 2023 - Feb 2024

Yandex (a leading tech company often likened to 'Russia's Google)

Remote

- $\ Analysed \ multivariate \ A/B \ tests \ {\rm on \ SERP \ to \ confirm \ the \ outcome \ of \ experiments, \ interpreting \ over \ 1000 \ metrics.}$
- Analysed experiments, delivering results in BI dashboards and presentations to let stakeholders gain insights and
 make informed decisions.
- Calculated metric sensitivity using nocode ML pipelines to improve data analysis accuracy.
- Technology used: Python, YQL, YTsaurus, DataLens (Tableau-like Data Visualization tool)

• Full-Stack Data Analyst (Analytics Engineer)

Nov 2022 - Jan 2023

Georgia, Tbilisi

 $3commas.io\ (a\ prominent\ cryptocurrency\ trading\ platform)$

- Implemented **data integrations** with third-party services APIs to ensure accurate and reliable data for analysis.
- Supported the team of analysts, conducting **data processing** and storage workflows using Airflow/Redshift pipelines.
- Implemented code-style rules and best SQL and practices for **git-based development**, improving collaboration and efficiency within the team of 12 data analysts.
- Transformed business requirements into data requirements to improve the core DWH, including dbt models.
- Technology used: SQL, Redshift, Airflow, Python, dbt

• Data Scientist

Sep 2019 - Sep 2022

MEL Science (an international edTech creating digital and physical products)

Russia, Saint Petersburg; Armenia, Yerevan

Maintained a consistent retention rate of the monthly subscription model at the 90% level throughout 3 years by

- Maintained a consistent retention rate of the monthly subscription model at the 90% level throughout 3 years by monitoring churn and other key metrics. Delivered insights with each fluctuation and prevented potential annual losses of up to \$200,000 per insight.
- Applied statistical survival analysis techniques with prediction to improve production estimates, achieving a 15% reduction in stock storage costs.
- Collaborated with product teams, consistently delivering insights and crafting ad-hoc queries to support new ideas and decision-making processes.
- Analyzed A/B tests to improve conversion rates, leading to their notable increase of 2-3%.
- Prepared data for monthly and annual reporting to stakeholders.
- Refined data strategy, organising stakeholder discussions to identify and prioritise key metrics crucial for organisational growth.
- Conducted a data analysis course for 10+ product stakeholders to enhance their data analysis skills.
- Mentored two analysts individually at different times, guiding their professional development and enhancing their expertise in financial and marketing analysis.
- Technology used: Python, PostgreSQL, dbt, Metabase, Google Analytics

• Data Scientist AppliedML (outsource AI-startup)

Mar 2019 - Aug 2019

Russia, Saint-Petersburg

- **Technology used**: Python, OpenCV

• Product Owner

Aug 2018 - Feb 2019

MotionLearning (NN-app for creating AI-generated educational video content)

Russia, Saint-Petersburg

EDUCATION

•Bachelor of Computer Science

2015 - 2019

Saint Petersburg State University, Saint Petersburg, Russia

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

•Founder

 $Sep\ 2021$ - Present

Analyst Girls Club (female-only professional community)

- Established a safe and supportive environment for 200 women from diverse backgrounds to excel in their careers.
- Developed and curated free educational resources, enhancing members' skills.
- Organized networking events, enabling members to forge meaningful connections, exchange ideas, and share unique experiences within a supportive and understanding community.
- Empowered women in data, system, and business analysis, actively promoting inclusivity and gender diversity within the industry.